Blood always follows money.
Hell or High Water is a western, crime, drama film directed by David Mackenzie.
A divorced dad and his ex-con brother resort to a desperate scheme
in order to save their family's farm in West Texas.
Marcus Hamilton, played by Jeff Bridges.
Toby Howard, played by Chris Pine.
Tanner Howard, played by Ben Foster.
Alberto Parker, played by Gil Birmingham.
Debbie Howard, played by Marin Ireland.
Billy Rayburn, played by Kevin Rankin.
Hell or High Water is a 2016 American neo-Western crime drama film
directed by David Mackenzie and written by Taylor Sheridan.
It follows two brothers (Chris Pine and Ben Foster) who carry out a series of bank robberies to save their
family ranch, while being pursued by two Texas Rangers (Jeff Bridges and Gil Birmingham).
It was the final film produced by OddLot
Entertainment before its dissolution in 2015.
Hell or High Water premiered at the Un Certain Regard section of the Cannes Film Festival on May
16, 2016, and was theatrically released in the United States on August 12, 2016.
It received critical acclaim, particularly for Pine, Foster, and
Bridges' performances, Sheridan's screenplay, and the editing.
It grossed $37.9 million on a $12 million budget.
The American Film Institute selected it as one of its 10 movies of the year, and it was nominated for numerous awards, including
four Oscar nominations: Best Picture, Best Supporting Actor (Bridges), Best Original Screenplay, and Best Editing.
The film is the second installment of writer Taylor Sheridan's American
Frontier Trilogy, along with Sicario and Wind River.
In 2022, it was reported that SK Global is developing a drama
series based on the film for the Fox network.
The film explores themes of brother, texas, bank robber, road trip, gun battle.
The tone is emotional.